carrentalexpress.com 2015-12-07

# Car Rental Express Privacy Policy

_Updated March 9, 2009_

## Information about Privacy on Car Rental Express.com

Express Internet Technologies Inc., the parent company of Car Rental Express.com, is committed to protecting your privacy. You can visit most pages on our site without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this privacy statement explains data collection and use in those situations.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact our support department via email at [help@carrentalexpress.com](mailto:help@carrentalexpress.com). This privacy policy statement covers only information that is collected through http://www.carrentalexpress.com, and does not cover information collected through any other site.

## Collection and Use of your Personal Information

We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you (personal information) or allows us to contact you. Generally, this information is requested when you are registering before entering a contest, ordering e-mail newsletters or securing a car rental reservation through our reservation system.

CarRentalExpress.com also collects certain information about your computer hardware and software. This information may include: your IP address, browser type, operating system, domain name, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of CarRentalExpress.com.

## Reservations

If you reserve a vehicle through http://www.carrentalexpress.com, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our reservation form. You must provide contact information (such as name, e-mail address, phone number, & street address) and may need to provide some financial information (such as credit card type, or credit card number & expiration date). We use this information to provide the rental agency with sufficient information to book the vehicle, and to contact you in advance if there is an issue concerning the rental. Also, we will be sending reminder emails etc. from time to time to assist in the reservation process.

When we transmit sensitive information (such as a credit card numbers) over the internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. We store the personal information you provide in computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities Your information, other than financial information is sent to the rental agency via email or fax. Financial information is only accessible through a secure, controlled area of the site only accessible to the car rental agency through the administrative work station via a strict authentication process. Agencies are unable to alter the information in any way.

## Surveys or Contests

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name, address, phone, zip, & e-mail address). We use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes, to monitor site traffic or personalize the site to send participants an email newsletter.

## Tell-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Car Rental Express stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email & and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [remove@carrentalexpress.com](mailto:remove@carrentalexpress.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

## Special Offers and Updates

We may occasionally send you information on car rental promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the "Choice and Opt-out" in the Control of your Personal Information section.

## Log Files

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. We use log files to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site such as:

  * Traffic 
    * Hour of Day Activity, Day of Week Activity, Day of Month Activity, Detail Daily Activity, Detail Weekly Activity, Monthly Activity, Views Per Visit, & Length Of Visit .
  * Visitors 
    * Who is on, Recent Spiders, Top Visitors, Top Spiders, Top Visitor Organizations, Top Spider Organizations, Top Visitors by Bandwidth, Top Spiders by Bandwidth, Authenticated Top Visitors, Top Visitor Countries, Top Spider Countries, Top Visitor Regions, & Top Spider Regions.
  * Pages 
    * Most Downloaded Files, Most Requested Pages, Top Static Pages, Top Dynamic Pages, Top Entry Pages / Files, Top Exit Pages / Files, Most requested Images, Most Requested Audio, Files, Most Requested Video Files, Most Requested Unknown Files, Site Bookmarked, Single Access Pages / Files, Most Downloaded File Types, Most Accessed Directories, & URL Parameter Query
  * Browsers 
    * Most Used Browsers, Firefox and Opera Browsers, Internet Explorer Browsers, Visiting Spiders, Download Managers, & Most Used Platforms
  * Capabilities 
    * Frame Support, VBScript Support, JavaScript Support, Java Applet Support, & ActiveX Support.
  * Referrers 
    * Top Referring Site by IP, Top Referring URLs, Top Search Engines, No Hits from Search Engine, Top Search Phrases, Top Search Keywords, & Search Phrases Per Engine.
  * Errors 
    * Server Errors, Summary of HTTP Errors, Requests causing Errors, & Detail Daily Errors.

This information is used to understand the demographic make-up of our web visitors.

## Disclosure

Car Rental Express will disclose your personal information only if required to do so by law, in the good faith belief that doing so protects the property of Car Rental Express, or to protect the safety of our employees and their families.

## Control of your Personal Information

### Choice and Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you reserve a vehicle but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form. If you do not wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [optout@carrentalexpress.com](mailto:optout@carrentalexpress.com). We also offer an opportunity to opt-out on our member information page (http://www.carrentalexpress.com/members)

You will be notified before personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

## Access to Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service(s), you may edit your information or opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [optout@carrentalexpress.com](mailto:optout@carrentalexpress.com). We also offer an opportunity to opt-out on our member information page (http://www.carrentalexpress.com/members)

## Security of your Personal Information

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our reservation forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). To learn more about SSL, follow this link: [http://www.geotrust.com](http://www.geotrust.com/). We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send an email to us at [support@carrentalexpress.com](mailto:support@carrentalexpress.com).

## Storage

Your information is stored in Canada, and in the future may be stored in any country where Car Rental Express has facilities. The same privacy policy will apply to your information no matter in which country it is stored.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use session ID cookie on this site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser or leave the browser idle for 30 minutes. We do not use persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site.

## Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Car Rental Express. Please be aware that we, Car Rental Express, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

## Co-branded sites

Car Rental Express co-brands with car rental agencies world-wide. All these agencies are under contract with Car Rental Express either individually or through marketing associations. Personally identifiable information collected by Car Rental Express for the purpose of a vehicle rental reservation is given to the selected car rental agency. This information is used only to process and facilitate the reservation and subsequent rental. This information is stored in Car Rental Express' database. Making the reservation is voluntary. If you do not want your personally identifiable information shared with your chosen car rental agency, please do not make the reservation through our automated system.

## Business Transitions

In the event Express Internet Technologies Inc. goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email and prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. You will be able to notify us if you do not wish your personally identifiable information to be transferred. You may email us at [info@carrentalexpress.com](mailto:info@carrentalexpress.com), write us at Express Internet Technologies Inc.

7 - 15715 34th Avenue Surrey, BC, CANADA, V3S 0J6

## The Nature of Express Internet Technologies Inc. Business

Express Internet Technologies Inc. (ExpressITech or EIT) is the parent company of Car Rental Express.com (CRX). ExpressITech provides reservation software services to Car-Rental Agencies (Agencies). This software system is called the Revolution Reservation System, and it powers reservations both on CRX and at private Agency web sites.

Car Rental Agencies are the direct customers of ExpressITech. Visitors to the Car Rental Express.com web site are direct customers of the Car Rental Agencies represented at the CRX site. ExpressITech functions much like the Yellow Pages does, enabling access to business services by the general public. The ExpressITech Better Business Bureau (BBB) accreditation is dependent on the relationship between ExpressITech and its Car Rental Agency customers. ExpressITech applies fair and reasonable business practices to its Agency customer base. ExpressITech.com support and contact information is directed to these Agencies.

When a renter experiences a difficulty with a particular Agency, either at CRX, or at the Agency web site, then the renter must resolve that issue with the Agency, with whom the renter has a direct business relationship. Agency business policies appear online to assist with that process. In the case where a renter raises a concern to ExpressITech or Car Rental Express.com, regarding a specific Agency or renting experience, then it is ExpressITech's role to forward that concern to the specified Agency. ExpressITech's role is one of facilitating and monitoring communications, not one of intervention or problem resolution.

## Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: email at privacy [support@carrentalexpress.com](mailto:support@carrentalexpress.com).

Please click here to view our Terms of Use Policy.

© Express Internet Technologies Inc., 1999 - 2010. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.
